A Guide to the Records of the 4-H All Stars, Virginia Chapter, 1964-2014
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the 4-H All Stars, Virginia Chapter, 1964-2014
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 26/4/1
4.2 Cubic Feet; 3 boxes
Founded in 1922, the Virginia 4-H All Stars are the highest honor for the Virginia 4-Hers, and membership is based on leadership, service, and activities. The records of the Virginia Chapter of the 4-H All Stars span the years 1964-2014. The collection includes minutes, correspondence, financial reports, bylaws and policies, membership rosters, and photographs. It also includes the organization's mission statement, constitution, and 75th anniversary materials. The collection also contains materials about the Interstate Order of 4-H All Stars and about the midwinter and summer conferences.
4-H All Stars. Virginia Chapter
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the 4-H All Stars, Virginia Chapter were donated to the Special Collections in 2005. Additional donations were received in 2010, 2011, and 2015.
Administrative History
The first All Star chapter was established in West Virginia in 1919, followed by the Maryland chapter in 1921. Three West Virginia All Stars helped the Virginia Chapter organize and launch with 12 members on August 4, 1922. All Star membership is the highest honor in each state's 4-H chapter and is based on leadership, service, and activities.
Scope and Content
The records of the Virginia Chapter of the 4-H All Stars span the years 1964-2014. The collection includes minutes, correspondence, financial reports, bylaws and policies, membership rosters, and photographs. It also includes the organization's mission statement and constitution. In addition to information about the local chapter, the collection contains materials about the Interstate Order of 4-H All Stars and about the midwinter and summer conferences.
The 75th Anniversary Folder contains a publication about the history of the Virginia Chapter of the 4-H All Stars, as well as a program of the festivities and a registration list for the celebration held in September 1997.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series. Materials within each series are organized alphabetically by subject matter and each subject is organized chronologically.
Series I: Administrative (Lists, bylaws/constitution, financial reports, and nominations)
Series II: Conferences (Anniversary conferences, Interstate, Midwinter and Summer)
Series III: Correspondence
Series IV: Minutes (Business and Executive Meetings)
Series V: Photographs
Series VI: Publication Information (relating to The Virginia Star)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Material
Copies of the serial publication, The Virginia Stars, were separated to the Rare Book Collection.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the 4-H All Stars, Virginia Chapter by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
4-H clubs; Agriculture
Organizations:
4-H All Stars. Virginia Chapter
Contents List
- Series I: Administrative, 1985-2007
  - Future Plans Committee, 1939-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitutional Bylaw Revisions, 1959-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - District Information, 1963-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agendas, 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Audit Committee Report, 1976-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bylaws and Policies, 1977-2009 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Parliamentary Procedure, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 4-H Compliance with Civil Rights and Title IX, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Past Big Chief Notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lesser Chief Job Description (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Policies, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee Reports, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nominations, 1985-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Nominations, 2002-2010 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - All Stars Recommendations and Nominations (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Annual Reports, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - All Stars Gamma Chapter, Big Chief's Annual Report, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - All Stars Guidelines and Policies, 2009-2011 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Concecration Ceremony, 1939-1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ceremony, Georgia Installation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - All Star Addresses, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hall of Fame Papers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Membership Study, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dues Paying Members, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Membership Committee, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Policy and Nominations, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Membership Documents, 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - District Chiefs, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Addresses, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Address Lists, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 4-H Congress Details and Applicants, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Committee Reports, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - New Member Documents, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Summer Conference, New Initiate Registration, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Member Nominees for All Stars, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Honorary Membership Applications, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Tapping Exceptions, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Initiate List, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 4-H All Star Members (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Executive Committee Addresses, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Financial Reports, 1988-2005 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - All Stars Finances and Budget, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Budget, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - All Stars Income Statement, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Financial, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Future Finances Committee, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Budget Committee Report (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - New All Star Recognition, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - New Member Recognition, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Unit Chapter Awards, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - C. Dean Allen Award, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - All Stars Forms for Applications and Awards (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bradshaw Award, 1977-1998 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Key Awards Brochure, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Awards & Scholarships, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Series II: Conferences, 1981-2010
  - Midwinter Conferences, 1992-2010 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Midwinters Conference, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Midwinters and Summer Conference, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Midwinter Conference, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 4-H All Star Midwinter Conference, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - All Star Conference Midwinters Conference, 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Summer Conference, 1991-2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Summer Conference, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Summer Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - All Stars Summer Conference, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - All Star Summer Conference, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Summer Conference Evaluations (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee, 1973-1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee Conference, 1991-2000 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Info, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Summer Conference Executive Committee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 50th Anniversary Reunion, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 60th Reunion, Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 60th Reunion Sheraton Banquet Problem, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 60th Reunion Evaluations, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 60th Reunion Budget, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 60th Reunion - Thursdays Lunch, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 60th Reunion Programs, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 60th Reunion Banquet, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 60th Reunion Registration Forms, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 60th Anniversary Conference, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 60th Anniversary Summer Conference Evaluation Summaries, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 75th Anniversary, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Interstate Conferences, 1959-1980 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Interstate Conferences, 1989-2009 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Interstate Documents, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 4-H Interstate Reports, 1979-2012 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - All Star Interstate Conferences, 2006-2010 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Holiday Inn Conference Center, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 4-H Congress, 1975-1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - All Star Luncheon, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 4-H State Conferences, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1983-2007
  - Conferences - District Officers, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence - Initiates, 1974-1991 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence - Committees, 1985-1995 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence and Nominations, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - All Stars Correspondence, 1992-2000 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2007 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Series IV: Minutes, 1984-2007
  - All Stars Chapter Minutes (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Past Big Chief (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1991-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes. Business & Executive Committees, 2002-2007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - All Stars Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Series V: Publications, 1964-2014
  - Big Chief's Newsletter, 1964-1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - All Stars Midwinters Pamplet, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - All Stars Pamphlets, 1980-2014 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Virginia Star, 1991-2006 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Virginia Star, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - All Star Jewelry, 1975-1997 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 4-H Ambassador Program, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - All Star Representative Form "Speaker's Bureau", 1989 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - All Star Nametags, 1974-1991 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Ceremony Only, 1985-1992 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1997-2001
  - Photographs, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 46)